welcome back
last episode we built a crucible
but couldn't manage to use it
but today it's going to be under the spotlight
or maybe I should say
over the fire that lights up the room
anyways
we prepare it with also some casting channels
then we throw inside it the stuff we want to melt
and unlike the forge
we can do alloys directly inside it
once the metal is liquid
we can pour it inside molds in various ways
which means either with casting channels
or directly in the crucible
the crucible is also big enough to fit our old anvils
thus allowing us to recycle all of our old stuff
but what we actually want to use it for is a blast furnace
and that thing is quite expensive
to build it
we have to break the piggy bank iron ingots we saved up in between episodes
and start hammering those into double iron plates
and after breaking a lot of stone hammers
we managed to craft a blast furnace
however
the controller on its own won't be enough
we also need a lot of fire clay bricks for the rest of the structure
and it was then that we ran out of graphite
thus we went back to our exhausted mine
where with a desperate cinematic action
we found a lot more of what we were looking for
with that we have the stuff we lacked of
and thus managed to build our blast furnace
it is composed by a crucible
the blast furnace on top
and then a chimney of firebricks shielded by iron plates
and we must not forget the bellows
to use our blast furnace
we climb on top of the chimney
and drop in some iron, some coal and some fluxing material
then we turn it on by firing up the mix with a fire starter kit
now we have to wait for it to heat up
adding some charcoal whenever it runs low
once our fuel reaches the maximum temperature
we punch the bellows
to push it to the temperature required for making steel
once the chemical process is done
the molten steel will fall inside the crucible below the blast furnace
where we can retrieve it using molds
to be more precise
what we got from this process is pig iron
to turn it into steel
we have to hammer it quite hard
to get all of the slag out
we keep hammering
until we convert it into high carbon steel
and then into normal steel
and that was the material for our anvil upgrade
but we can do better
we can alloy some other materials into our steel
to make it stronger
and I know this looks like it's weaker
but if we takes this weak steel
weld it with some pig iron
and keep hitting it
we eventually get black steel
which makes for an even better anvil
but we can do even better
we can alloy even more stuff with our different steels
to get blue steel
or
this time
we also have a second equivalent tiered material
red steel
other than the color
the difference between the two is just what kind of extra materials they have in their compound
and to strengthen those two new variants
we have to add some black steel
and keep smashing with our hammer
that means a lot of anvil work
and with that we now have a red steel anvil
this with also blue steel on the same level
is the highest tier
and the thing it will allow us to do is to craft colorful steel buckets
which should be able to withstand the heat from lava
talking of heat
all of that time working next to our forge with hot metals
is giving us heat stroke issues
to avoid getting a too high fever
we shall go outside and take a bath in our pool
after our bath
we can go back to work
where we forge a bucket of the other color
and now
that we have a bucket of each one of the endgame TerraFirm materials
we can merge them together to get the ultimate bucket
the vanilla one
with that
we have completed all of what matter of the primitive age tier
and we are ready to get our factory started
the first machine we will need are the steam ones
and as usual
we shall get a high pressure steam solar boiler
other than avoiding the toxic lead surrounding the silver
we faced a second issue
the purity of our glass
glass we made so far is volcanic due to the black sand we used
that makes it too opaque for a solar boiler
so we went to a not too far river to gather white sand
the only one that makes crystal clear glass
with that we have made our first solar powered boiler
which shall stay on the roof
this machine will need water
and for the moment
the only way we found to do so is to manually insert it
to buffer the produced steam
we can store some in a bronze drum
which will then feed our steam workshop
and our first machine shall be a forge hammer
this machine will basically do most of the anvil jobs
most notably
we get 50% more plates out of our ingots
it can also smash carbon out of iron blooms and high carbon ingots
but that takes a lot of time
our next machine shall be an alloy smelter
followed by a compressor
a macerator
and finally after making a little bit more of room
an extractor
the next step in our progression is to make rubber
that requires some resin which is made by kapok, a tropical tree
which we already brought back home from the kaolinite clay trip
to extract it resin
we could put its wood in an extractor
but a better way is to extract it with a tap
filling up a whole bucket with this stuff
will take enough time to make us question
if using a steam machine would have been a better option
but we use this meditation time to instead look for better stuff to do
（向上合并）
thus we started working on making some gears to expand our workshop
and to make those spin
we shall use the iconic water well
now that we have achieved kinetic energy
we can power a press to increase our plate yield
the process is quite slow
so we add some gears to speed up the process
for more advanced machines
we will need electron tubes
the main issue here is that we will be needing a lot of resin
（向上合并）
so we go back to our latex collection process
to process it we need some sulfur
but the main issue is finding a way that is easy to automate
and of that seems to be the best choice
it also uses less sulfur
the issue is that it is made with wax
so we built some beehives in a field of flowers
usually it takes some weeks
but we got lucky
and managed to attract two bees in a couple of days
we retrieve the wax and build the vat
but since we can't automate it
we shall buffer latex with a drum
next we manually place it in the vat
add the sulfur and let it process
since that was taking too much time
we also use the pot recipe
and since that one was slow too
we made more pots
and this is when we realized
we should have placed the vat above the fire
now that we have resin
it's just a matter of smaller easier tasks before we can get the electron tube
we use those to craft some deployers
so that we can start assembling vacuum tubes
those are part of our next major progress breakthrough
electric circuits
but before we get there
we have one more major issue, rubber
（向上合并）
we can easily get it from working resin
but we are not making enough
and to make thing worse
our production is soon going to halt for a couple of months
so we instead opt for extracting the logs
this means we will need even more wood
while we can easily gather it
I think manually collecting it is a barbaric thing to do with our current technology
（向上合并）
to automate such task
we start by getting a source of perpetual motion
and we need some solid structure
to prevent the dirt from breaking it
now that we have a spinning block surrounded by a nice field
we build a long arm
that will support the tools for chopping trees and planting new ones
（向上合并）
we add a system to manage the extraction of the collected wood
（向下合并）
finally, we glue everything into a single chunky machine
and connect the missing shaft to make it work
and there we have it
our automated tree farm
for trees to grow it will take some time
in the meanwhile
we can work with what we already have
to get some rubber to get started
and while this was the last material preventing us from making LV circuits
we don't have enough resin for making enough
and the main issue is that
we won't be able to make any more for the next 3 months
we can spend this time by playing minesweeper between the toxic ores and the falling rocks
and as you probably noticed
we are looking for silver
so that we can expand our solar boiler farm
to power our growing automation
however it is now winter
and our automation decided to go on vacation
we use that time to go warm up
by doing some manual work
but
working like that is giving us the wrong kind of sweat
so
after getting cold sweats in the jellied winter caves
we go work in the hot sauna of our blast furnace
and after the great sadness of manually pouring out ingots
we figured out a better way of doing it
we cool down the white hot steel by making it move through a copper pump
with that
we can easily work iron in all of its forms
we spend the rest of the winter stacking up ingots over ingots over ingots of it
until it is time to put it to good use during the upcoming spring
while that steel is enough for many LV machine hulls
we are limited by other materials such as red steel
for now we can only make four hulls
and this was just the easy part of LV machines
now that it's February
the latex started dripping out of the kapok trees again
we quickly gathers lots of it
and boil it with some sulfur to obtain resin
which we can use to make the resistors and circuit boards we were lacking of
for the next thing we needed for the LV tier, electric circuits
（向上合并）
now that we have those
we just have to quickly craft a bunch of motors
to unlock the LV tier
and since this is going to be a whole new age
I think we can close this episode here
bye bye
欢迎回来
上一集我们搭了个坩埚
但无法使用它
但今天它将成为焦点
或者也许我应该说
在照亮房间的火上
不管怎样
我们还准备了一些铸造通道
然后我们把想融化的东西扔进去
不像铁匠铺
我们可以直接在里面做合金
一旦金属变成液体
我们可以通过各种方式将其倒入模具中
这意味着要么使用铸造通道
或者直接在坩埚里
坩埚也足够大，可以容纳我们的旧铁砧
这样我们就可以回收所有的旧东西
但我们实际上想把它用在高炉上
那东西很贵。
建造它
我们要打碎在剧集间隙攒下的存钱罐铁锭
开始把它们锤成双层铁板
在打碎了很多石锤之后
我们设法制造了一个高炉
然而
控制器本身是不够的
我们还需要大量的耐火粘土砖用于结构的其余部分
就在那时，我们的石墨用完了。
于是我们回到了我们精疲力尽的矿井
用一个绝望的电影动作
我们找到了更多我们要找的东西
这样我们就有了我们缺少的东西
从而成功建造了我们的高炉
它是由坩埚组成的
顶部的高炉
然后是铁板保护的耐火砖烟囱
我们不能忘记风箱
使用我们的高炉
我们爬上烟囱顶
再放些铁煤和助焊剂进去
然后我们用起火套件点燃混合物来打开它
现在我们要等它升温
木炭快用完的时候再加一些
一旦我们的燃料达到最高温度
我们击打风箱
把它推到炼钢所需的温度
一旦化学过程完成
钢水会掉进高炉下面的坩埚里
在那里我们可以用模具取回它
更准确地说
我们从这个过程中得到的是生铁
把它变成钢铁
我们得使劲敲
把所有的渣都弄出来
我们不断锤击
直到我们将其转化为高碳钢
然后变成普通钢
那是我们铁砧升级的材料。
但我们可以做得更好
我们可以用合金把其他材料制成我们的钢
让它更强大
我知道这看起来更弱
但如果我们用这种弱钢
用生铁焊接一下
并继续打它
我们最终会得到黑钢
这是一个更好的铁砧
但我们可以做得更好
我们可以用不同的钢合金更多的东西
得到蓝钢
或者
这一次
我们还有第二个等效的分层材料
红钢
除了颜色
两者之间的区别只是他们的化合物中有什么样的额外材料
并加强这两个新变种
我们得加点黑钢
继续用我们的锤子砸
这意味着要做很多铁砧工作
现在我们有了一个红色的铁砧
这也和蓝钢在同一等级
是最高级
它让我们可以制作彩色钢桶
能够承受岩浆热量的桶
说到热量
一直在铁匠铺工作
让我们快中暑了
为避免发高烧
我们到外面的泳池里泡泡澡
泡完澡
我们可以回去工作了
我们锻造出其他颜色的桶
而现在
我们有群峦毕业材料做成的桶
把它们合并在一起得到“桶·终极版”
原版的桶
有了那个
我们已经完成了原始人时期的所有事情
我们准备好开始工业化了
我们需要的第一台机器是蒸汽机器
和往常一样
我们要做一个进阶太阳能锅炉
除了要避免银周围的毒铅
我们面临着第二个问题
玻璃的纯度
到目前为止，因为使用了黑色沙子，我们制作的玻璃是火山的（？）
这使得它对太阳能锅炉来说太不透明了
所以我们去了不太远的河边收集白沙
它是唯一能制造出水晶般透明的玻璃的物品
有了它，我们制造了第一台太阳能锅炉
而它应该待在屋顶上
这台机器需要水
就目前而言
我们发现唯一办法是手动输入
要缓存产生的蒸汽
我们可以把一些蒸汽储存在铜桶里
然后供给蒸汽车间
我们的第一台机器是锻造锤
这台机器可以完成大部分铁砧工作
最显著的
锭能多生产50%的板
它还可以敲出铁块（？）和高碳锭中的碳
但那需要很多时间
我们的下一台机器将是合金冶炼炉
然后是压缩机
研磨机
最后在腾出更多的空间之后
提取器
下一步是制造橡胶
这需要一些由热带树木木棉制成的树脂
我们已经从高岭土之旅中带回家了
要提取树脂
我们可以用提取器提取橡胶木
但更好的方法是用木龙头
把这东西装满一整桶
所花的时间让足以让我们质疑
使用蒸汽机是否是更好的选择
但我们反过来用这段冥想时间去找更好的事情做
（向上合并）
因此，我们开始制作一些齿轮来扩建车间
要让它们旋转
我们将使用标志性的水车
现在我们已经获得了动能
我们可以启动动力冲压机来提高板的产量
加工相当缓慢
所以我们增加了一些齿轮来加速
对于更高级的机器
我们需要电子管
主要问题是我们需要大量的树脂
（向上合并）
所以我们接着收集乳胶
我们需要一些硫来处理它
但主要问题是找到一种易于自动化的方法
这似乎是最好的选择
它也使用更少的硫
问题是它是用蜂蜡做的
所以我们在花田里建了一些蜂箱
通常需要几周时间
但我们很幸运
在几天内吸引了两只蜜蜂
我们取回蜂蜡并造出桶（？）
但既然我们不能自动化它
就用筒（？）暂存乳胶
接下来我们手动将其放入桶中
加入硫让它处理
因为那需要太多时间
我们也开始用陶罐（？）配方
因为陶罐配方也很慢
我们做了更多的陶罐
这时我们意识到
我们应该把桶放在火上
现在我们有树脂了
再花点小功夫做出电子管
我们用电子管来制造一些机械手
这样我们就可以开始组装真空管了
这些是我们下一个重大突破的一部分
电路板
但在我们造出它之前
还有一个大问题，橡胶
（向上合并）
我们可以很容易地通过处理树脂得到它
但是产量远远不够
更糟糕的是
我们的生产很快就要停止几个月了
所以我们选择提取原木
这意味着我们需要更多的木材
虽然我们可以很容易地收集它
以我们现在的科技水平，手动收集太野蛮了
（向上合并）
要自动化此类任务
我们从造出永动机开始
我们需要一些坚实的支撑结构
以防止泥土破坏它
现在我们有了一个被漂亮土地包围的旋转方块
我们搭一个长臂
用来放砍树的工具并种植新的树苗
（向上合并）
我们增加了一个系统来管理收集到的木材的提取
（向下合并）
最后，我们把所有东西都粘在一台厚实的机器上
连接缺失的传动杆让它正常工作
完工
我们的自动化树场
树木的生长需要一些时间
同时
我们可以利用现有的资源
先做出点橡胶
虽然这是阻止我们制作LV电路板的最后材料
我们没有足够的树脂来制造足够的电路板
主要问题是
在接下来的3个月里，我们将无法再生产任何东西
我们可以在有毒矿石和落石之间玩扫雷
你可能也注意到了
我们在找银
这样我们就可以扩建太阳能锅炉
为我们日益增长的自动化提供动力
然而现在是冬天
自动化产线也打算放寒假
我们利用这段时间让身子暖起来
通过一些手工劳作
但是
那样工作会让我们出汗
所以
在凛冽的冬季洞穴里出完冷汗后
我们到高炉构成的热桑拿房里工作
在经历手动倒出液态金属的巨大痛苦之后
我们想出了更好的办法
我们让白热的钢通过铜泵来冷却它
有了那个
我们可以很容易地加工各种形式的铁
我们整个冬天都在屯屯屯金属锭
直到春天到来，能够好好利用它们
虽然这种钢足以制造许多LV机器外壳
我们受到红钢等其他材料的限制
目前我们只能做四个外壳
这还只是LV机器中简单的部分
现在是二月
胶乳又开始从木棉树上滴下来了
我们很快收集了很多
和一些硫一起煮，得到树脂
我们可以用它来制造我们缺少的电阻器和基板
来做我们接下来在LV电压需要的电路板
（向上合并）
现在我们有了那些东西
只需要快速制造一堆马达
就能解锁LV电压
既然这将是一个全新的时代
我想可以就此结束这一集
拜拜